

OBJECTIVES

I would like to work as a Software Engineer and put my accumulated expertise from numerous projects and courses over the last few years to use. I am looking forward to contributing and as well as learning new technologies from time to time.

+88015-2143-1502

shahariaresha@gmail.com

Abdullah Esha

EDUCATION

Bachelor Of Science in Computer Science and Engineering (2018– 2021)

American International University - Of Bangladesh

Higher Secondary School Certificate (2016)

BAF Shaheen College, Dhaka 1206

Secondary School Certificate (2014)

Maniknagar Model High School, Dhaka 1203

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Node js, React js, React Native C, C++, Java, C#, Nest js HTML5, CSS3, MUI, jQuery, Ajax, JSON MSSQL, PostgreSQL Docker, Jenkins Postman Linux (Security Onion, Ubuntu)

Trello. GitLab

ABDULLAH **ESHA**

Software Engineer

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Info Inlet

Software Engineer (June 2024 - Present)

Currently, collaborating with a team on a large-scale project, with a primary focus on front-end development. Some other tasks may be assigned according to company requirements also worked on that.

Swop Technologies

Software Engineer (May 2023 - Dec 2023)

After a certain period started working with Next JS and Express JS and excelled in delivering complex, client-specific functionalities in comparatively more challenging projects. Additionally, I managed deployments on AWS (EC2) and worked with cPanel for hosting tasks.

Junior Software Engineer (May 2022 - Apr 2023)

Contributed to React JS and Laravel (API) based projects, specializing in static websites with user-friendly UI based on Figma. Key role in SEO optimization.

Atropos

IT Officer (Jan 2022 - Mar 2022)

Managed updates and maintenance of the official website, ensuring its accuracy and relevance.

Internship (Oct 2021 - Dec 2021)

I completed small learning projects using HTML5, CSS3, and PHP, gaining valuable experience in web development.

CORE SKILLS

Programming Language

JavaScript, Typescript

Frameworks

Express.js, Next js, Vite js, FastAPI

Web Technologies

Tailwind CSS, JWT, Firebase Auth, Redux, RTK Query, TanStack Query, jQuery, RESTful API etc.

SOL and Database

MySQL, MongoDB

Project deployment and version control

GitHub, Git Bash, cPanel, AWS(EC2)

CERTIFICATES

Crash Course on Python (Jul 2020)

An online non-credit course authorized by Google and offered through Coursera.

CyberOps Associate (Dec 2021)

An online course authorized by CISCO and offered by AIUB.

Paper: Assisting the Power Generation Sector Toward Sustainability-an IoT Based... (March 2022)

A paper published on ACM Digital Libary

AWARDS

Dean's Award (2018)

American International University of Bangladesh.

LANGUAGES

- English
- Bengali

INTERESTS

- Playing Football
- Reading Books

REFERENCES

RAIHAN UDDIN AHMED

Assistant Professor Department of Computer Science. ruabng2008@gmail.com American International University Bangladesh.

Rakibul Islam

Software Engineer irakibul568@gmail.com \$wop Technologies

PROJECTS

Butterfly Matrimonial V2.0 (Jul 2022 - Aug 2022)

React JS, Redux, Laravel 9, MySql

- A digital matchmaking platform aims to collect comprehensive bio-data from individuals.
- This data forms the basis for advanced analytical and sorting tools featured on this platform.
- Offers a sophisticated and efficient matchmaking experience.

SWOP V2.0 (Mar 2023 - Jun 2023)

Next JS, Express JS, MongoDB, Stripe

- Developed an e-commerce website for buying and selling NFC chips.
- Integrated SendGrid for automated emails (order confirmation, password recovery, and subscriber alerts).
- Implemented Stripe for secure payment processing.
- Utilized JWT authentication for user security and data protection.
- Created a comprehensive dashboard with analytics for transaction and performance tracking.

Bayshor Communication V3.0 (Feb 2023)

Next JS, Typescript, MongoDB

- Developed a marketing and software solution agency website using TypeScript and Next.js 13.5 (app router).
- Provided dashboard control to manage various aspects of the website.
- First professional experience working with TypeScript and Next.js.

Nazaara (Jun 2023 - Feb 2024)

Next js, Express js, Typescript, MongoDB, Firebase

- Developed a women's wear e-commerce website with customizable content via the dashboard.
- Connected to an outlet management system through an API.
- Integrated SendGrid for email notifications and SSLCommerz for payments with partial payment options.
- Implemented JWT authentication and analytics on both the website and dashboard.
- Some key features are still in development.

Common Ecommerce Backend (Jan 2024)

Node js, Express js, Typescript, MongoDB, JWT

- Built a simple backend as a personal learning project.
- Explored file structure, modern technologies, and problem-solving techniques.
- Gained valuable insights and improved confidence for future projects.